Curriculum Vitae

Julien COLOMB, PhD in Biology Schillerpromenade 4 12049 Berlin julien.colomb@fu-berlin.de 030 46721825

https://github.com/jcolomb http://orcid.org/0000-0002-3127-5520

Birth: 9 April 1979 in Sion (CH) Married, two children Swiss



Summary

After 12 years spent on fundamental research (neuro-genetics) in which I gathered skills in experimental design, team leading and student teaching, I got most interested in open science and research reproducibility as well as the digital tools helping scientists to achieve it. I would like to apply these novel knowledge to bring open science principles forward.

Research activities

2017 - 2018	Postdoctoral fellow, HU (Berlin, Germany), by Prof. Y. Winter
2015 - 2016	R Shiny applications to analyse and archive behaviour sequence data. Postdoctoral fellow, HU & Charité (Berlin , Germany), by Prof. Y. Winter
2014 - 2015	Animal core facility director and project manager. Postdoctoral fellow, HU & Charite (Berlin , Germany), by Prof. Y. Winter
2009 -2013	working on Phenobase. Postdoctoral fellow, FU (Berlin , Germany), by Prof. B. Brembs
2007-2008	working on "the what and where of operant learning in <i>Drosophila</i> ". Postdoctoral fellow, ESPCI (Paris , France), by Dr. T. Preat
	working on "appetitive learning in <i>Drosophila</i> ".

Commercial activities

2016-present Freelance scientist,

Animal core facility (Charité): organisation lead, data analysis in R, Phenobase

(Exist, HU): preclinical literature curation.

2012-present Founder and CEO of Drososhare GmbH (Berlin, Germany), facilitating fruit fly

transactions between scientists

Education

2016	FELASA B. HU Berlin
2013	Moderation & management (Continuing Education), FU Berlin/Artop.
2006	PhD in Biology, University of Fribourg (Fribourg , Switzerland).

PhD dissertation: "The chemosensory system of *Drosophila* larvae: neu-

roanatomy and behaviour" Thesis director: Prof. R.F Stocker

2002 Diploma in Biology, University of Fribourg (Fribourg, Switzerland)

1998 "Maturité fédérale type C" (scientific subsection), in the "Collège de la royale

Abbaye de St. Maurice"

Languages

French (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (fluent), Spanish (basics).

Research output

11 Research Papers (7 first author, 1 last author), 4 Reviews, 1 Scienceopen Collection

4 Open Source Software (3 main author),

3 Approved Grants

> 25 Meeting Presentations

see https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3127-5520, https://github.com/jcolomb:

Supervision of student

2010-2014	Co-supervisor of the PhD student Christine Damrau (with Dr. B.Brembs) on
2008	the role of octopamine in reward, motivation and motor control in <i>Drosophila</i> . Co-supervisor of the PhD student Séverine Trannoy (with Dr. G. Isabel and Dr. N. Gervasi) on the role of dopamine in appetitive learning consolidation in
2005	Drosophila. Co-supervisor of the diploma work of Claire Huguenin (with Dr. A. Ramaekers) on the role of NO in olfactory discrimination in Drosophila larvae.

Teaching experience

2016	Animal models of neuropathy, (master student, 2x2h lecture, organisation)
2012 2012 2011	Genetik (bachelor student, 2 x 3 h. lecture, 2x 1h. seminar) Neurogenetik. (master student, 2 x 2 h. lecture, 2x 1h. seminar) Practical course neurobiology. (7 x 4 h., Practical course supervision)
2011	Entwicklung der Insekten [Insect development] (2 h. lecture)
2006 2003-2006	Fluorescence and Confocal Microscopy (master student, 3h. lecture) Studying behavior. (master student, 2 h. lecture)
2003-2005	Developmental- and Neurogenetics (master student, 2 h. lecture).

Computer skills

Organisation: Outlook, Access, labfolder; Publishing: LATEX, Office, overleaf, markdown, html, figshare; Image processing: Photoshop, Illustrator, Image J; Programming and data analysis: R, Rmarkdown, shiny, Git, Labview; Collaborative working: Github, redmine

Other tasks

Organisation of the Berlin Open Science meetup Part of the march for science Berlin Orga team 2017 Creation of the T. Preat's and R.F. Stocker's lab website. Co-director in the theater group "les apostrophes" in 2006